This is Charlie, a Defence Employee
Let’s see Charlie’s attitude towards
security in this scenario
It’s Monday morning and Charlie is
finishing his breakfast. On the Radio
that morning there’s a breaking news
story on an incident affecting Defence
capability and information
due to suspected cyber activity
Charlie doesn’t pay particular
attention to the news, he’s getting
ready for a busy day, when he’s done
he rushes out the door
Driving to work Charlie hears
the breaking news story again
The story talks about a website
exposing classified Defence
information related to millions of
dollars of high tech equipment
Still not paying much attention
to the story, Charlie changes channel
to listen to some music
When Charlie arrives at work his
workmates are talking about the leak
It was apparently hacked from someone’s
personal email account. They’re
wondering who in their right mind would
send classified information from the
DPN to their home email account?
Charlie remembers he sent classified
information to his Gmail last Friday
because he wanted to save time
to meet project deadlines
Charlie’s workmates explain how he has
compromised the information, risked
Defence’s reputation and put the
entire project at risk
Charlie explains he was just trying
to be efficient and meet the deadline
Charlie is informed that senior
management have been in the boardroom
all morning discussing the
Security incident
Charlie becomes greatly concerned
He thinks about how this could affect
him. Will he lose his job, what could
this mean for his family? He didn’t
mean to cause Defence’s
reputation harm
The boardroom door opens and Charlie
is immediately requested to come in
Charlie’s actions weren’t unintentional
they were deliberate
If he listened to his Security Officer
about protecting Official Information
or paid attention when completing his
Annual Security Awareness Course he
would have understood exactly
what could happen to him